《超感警探》前情提要
Previously on "The Mentalist"...
我们有个扑克牌局
Listen, there's this poker game we've got going on.
-想来吗  -也许吧  什么时候
- You want in? - Maybe. When?
我想想  星期四晚
Let me see-- Thursday night.
你要去玩扑克
You're going to play poker.
特蕾莎  很高兴你来了
Hey. Teresa. Glad you made it.
-这位是地检官唐·沃尔科特  -您好
- This is District Attorney Don Wolcott. - Hi.
联调局局长查尔斯·贝利
FBI Bureau Director Charles Bailey.
-您好  -参议员艾琳·道金斯
- Sir. - Senator Eileen Dawkins.
是州议员
State Senator.
来了这么多高层人士
It's a pretty high-class crowd.
你早跟我说一声就好了
I wish you would have warned me.
我想这位你认识  对吗
Oh, I think you know this guy, right?
特蕾莎  我没想过你会喜欢赌博
Teresa. I didn't take you for a gambler.
如果知道自己赢定了  就不算是赌了
It's not gambling if you know you're gonna win.
红心A
Ace of hearts.
不跟
Not me.
法官先生  看你的了
Action's on you, Judge.
那就
Well...
五百美元
$500.
庄家封牌
Dealer folds.
伯特仑  比你多了五百美元
That's $500 more to you, Bertram.
加注一千
Raise it $1,000.
你在虚张声势
You're bluffing.
全押上
All in.
我喜欢跟你打牌  盖尔
I love playing with you, Gale.
看透你就跟读儿童读物一样容易
I can read you like a kids' book.
随你说  拿走你的筹码吧
Yeah, yeah. Just pick up your chips.
"晚安  月亮"
"Goodnight moon."
源自美国儿童读物《晚安  月亮》
抱歉  失陪了各位  有个案子
I'm sorry, guys, but we caught one.
-能帮我兑现吗  -好的
- Will you cash me out? - Yeah.
玩得愉快
Have fun.
北加州大学  自然历史博物馆
你在这
There you are.
没尸体的时候
I should come by sometime
我也该常来这里看看
when there's not a corpse here to meet us.
你又去玩扑克了吗  里斯本
Are you playing poker again, Lisbon?
你被扑克打垮了
It's getting the better of you.
输钱了
Losing money?
腿毛都输光了
Losing skin's more like it.
伯特仑状态不好
Bertram's been in a bad mood.
你好  我是加调局的里斯本探员
Hi. I'm Agent Lisbon with the CBI.
克里斯托·帕帕达基斯
Christos Papadakis.
我是校自然科学系主任
I am Dean of the university's Natural Science Department,
博物馆是由我负责的
So... the museum is my responsibility.
请跟我来
Please follow me.
你们就是上次调查
I believe your team is the one
门特洛教授遇害案的小组吧
who investigated the death of professor Montero.
是的
Yeah, we were.
要走一段路
We have a bit of a walk.
博物馆的实验室在东翼
The museum labs are in the east wing of the museum.
对死者的情况你有多少了解
What can you tell us about the victim?
我们认为死者是琳达·帕弗瑞
We think it is Linda Parfrey.
你们认为是她
You think it's her?
琳达失踪了好一阵子了  而且...
Linda has been missing for some time, and...
你们很快就知道了
Well, you'll see.
这位是发现琳达的学生
Ah, this is the student who found Linda.
告诉他们你的名字
Tell--tell them your name.
我叫格雷  格雷戈里·刘易斯
Uh, Greg. Uh, Gregory Lewis.
我是大约午夜的时候发现她的
I found her around midnight.
说说事发经过
Tell me what happened.
全凭运气  我找到了一只非常好的树鼩
Well, by sheer luck, I-I happened upon a very nice tree shrew.
我从未研究过树鼩
Um, I've never examined one before,
就把它带回来准备去除皮肉
and I-I brought it in to strip the flesh off.
就是只保留骨架
You know, to keep the skeleton.
这怎么做
How do you do that?
把它们放到这些箱子里
Oh, w-we put 'em in these tanks.
这又怎么把骨架和皮肉分离开来
How does that strip them of their flesh?
-食尸虫  -食尸虫  对
- Flesh-eating bugs. - Flesh-eating bugs. Right.
没错
Right.
我就是这样发现琳达的
That's when I found linda.
没事了
Oh! Okay.
人人影视
YYeTs.com
原创翻译  双语字幕
■
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新
请登陆www.YYeTs.com
■
翻译：灰灰是菇凉 非燕 那时花开 Bony Michael 面条打包子  时间轴：玖月
超感警探
第五季
第十四集
■
时间轴：烟幕迟迟   校对：灰灰是菇凉  非燕  Bony  王小麦
第五季
第十四集
■
特效&后期：灰灰是菇凉   总监：灰灰是菇凉
失踪  琳达·帕弗瑞
对  是琳达的戒指
Yeah, that's Linda's ring, all right.
那死者就是琳达·帕弗瑞
So it is Linda Parfrey.
为何要弃尸于虫箱里
Why dump a body into a beetle tank?
博物馆安保措置不佳
The museum doesn't have great security,
但也没到能随随便便把尸体运出去的地步
but it's not the kind of place you can sneak a body out of.
除非尸体小到能装进行李袋
Unless you make it small enough to fit in a duffel bag.
凶手是在等虫子将尸体啃食至
So the killer was waiting for the bugs to eat it
只剩骨架  然后再偷运出去
down to the skeleton so they could sneak it out?
有可能  我们在箱子里发现了一件科学器械
Possibly. Uh, we found a scientific tool in the tank.
有可能是凶器
It could be the murder weapon.
凶手也许也是一名科学家
So the killer's probably another scientist then.
或者是博物馆的工作人员
Or someone that works at the museum.
最后一次看见琳达是什么时候
When was Linda last seen?
琳达已经失踪好几星期了
Linda's been missing a couple weeks.
大家以为她是去
People thought she was out camping
约塞米蒂国家公园做什么研究去了
near Yosemite doing some kind of research.
后来有人注意到她的车停在校园里
Then someone noticed her car was on campus,
才意识到她失踪了
and they realized she was missing.
是谁填的失踪人口报告
Who filed the missing persons report?
索尼亚·基德博士
Dr. Sonia Kidd.
她是校生物系主任
Head of the Biology Department at the university
也是琳达的顾问
and Linda's adviser.
名字听起来很耳熟
Her name sounds familiar.
是的  她写过几本书
Yeah, she's written a couple books.
流行科学读物  有一本叫
Popular science stuff. One's called
《天生杀手:谋杀的进化根源》
"Natural born killers: The evolutionary roots of murder."
有趣  我和简去找她谈谈
Cute. Jane and I will go talk to her.
琳达在博物馆有间办公室
And, uh, Linda had an office here at the museum.
你和周去查看一下
You and Cho check it out.
收到  头儿
You got it, boss.
我们以为她在山里迷路了
We thought she was lost in the mountains.
没想到她一直都在这里
But she was here the whole time.
简直太可怕了
It's too horrible for words.
她研究什么  研究哪种动物
What did she study? What kind of animal?
有什么关系吗
Why does that matter?
没有人会因为偶然而选择其终身事业
Nobody picks what they dedicate their life to by accident.
都是有原因的
It says something.
我研究灵长类动物大脑
I study primate brains.
这能说明我是怎样的人
What does that say about me?
你有一些阴暗的思想
You have dark thoughts inside your head
但你觉得它们很正常很自然
that you want to believe are normal and natural.
当然它们确实是那样
Which they are, of course.
琳达是研究鸟类的
Linda was an ornithologist.
她的博士生项目是研究北扑翅鴷的饮食
Her doctorate was on the diet of the northern flicker.
北扑翅鴷是一种啄木鸟
A kind of woodpecker.
有意思
Interesting.
啄木鸟十分执着
Tenacious.
不断用头撞树直到问题解决
Bang their head against the problem until they solve it.
琳达也是这种性格吗
Was that Linda?
是的
It was.
但是啄木鸟并不是用头撞树
Although woodpeckers don't bang their heads
而是用喙在树上钻洞
against things so much as they use their bills to drill holes.
的确  潜意识这东西
Yes. Well, the subconscious mind is--
没那么准
isn't really a stickler about that kind of thing.
她是个好学生吗
Uh, was she a good student?
她很聪明
Brilliant.
她已经和人合作在著名期刊上
She had already co-authored several papers
发表了好几篇论文了
in prestigious journals.
有谁嫉妒她吗
Well, who was jealous?
没有
Nobody.
我们的生物系在整个西海岸是顶尖的
This is the top biology department on the west coast.
这里的人都是精英
Best and brightest only.
每一个人的成功对我们都有好处
The success of one of us helps all of us.
我们是一家人
We're a family.
每天都有谋害亲人的事发生
Well, people murder family members every day.
这很自然
It's natural.
谋杀是一件自然的事
Murder is natural.
但却不正常
But abnormal.
教授们不会了解丑闻
Teachers don't know there's scandals
除非他们自己深陷其中
unless of course they are the scandal.
你们问完了吗
Are we done?
暂时问完了
Yeah. For now.
我们得跟几个学生谈谈
Uh, we're gonna need to talk to some students
还得去一趟礼品店
and visit the gift shop,
出门左拐  对吗
which is left out the door, isn't it?
打扰一下  你在做什么
Excuse me. What are you doing?
你们是什么人
Who are you?
我是瑞斯比探员  这位是周探员
I'm Agent Rigsby. This is Agent Cho.
我们是加调局的  你是谁
We're with CBI. And you are?
梅根·帕克
Megan Parker.
我是琳达博士课题的同学
I was Linda's classmate in the doctoral program.
我的办公室就在隔壁
And I have the office next door.
你在这做什么
What are you doing here?
我想在你们把这里封锁之前
I just came to get my copy of "Understanding macro-evolution"
拿走我的《理解宏观进化》的拷贝
before you guys sealed the place off.
你跟琳达熟悉吗
Did you know Linda well?
她是这里的明星
She was a rock star.
也许需要打扮下  但确实是明星
A rock star who could use a makeover, but still.
她拿到了今年的院长奖学金
She got the Dean's fellowship this year.
大约有10万块
That's like 100 grand.
而我们这些人只能用社保金
The rest of us will be paying off our student loans
去交我们的助学贷款
with our social security checks.
怎么会有这么多动物标本
What's with all the taxidermy?
琳达不是研究啄木鸟的吗
I thought Linda just studied woodpeckers.
管理标本室是琳达勤工俭学的工作
No, Linda managed the specimen rooms for her work-study,
她精力旺盛嘛
so she got the overflow.
毒品吗
Huh. Drugs?
是糖
Sugar.
她不吸毒
She didn't do drugs.
连无糖汽水也不喝
Not even diet soda.
她的私生活怎么样
What about her personal life?
-什么意思  -她有男朋友吗
- What about it? - Did she have one?
我们没怎么谈论过这个话题
We didn't talk about that stuff very much.
我知道她有个校外的男朋友
I know she had a boyfriend outside the school.
但仅此而已
But that's all I know.
简  收到留言后给我回电话
Hey, Jane, call me when you get this.
我想我找到琳达的同学了
I think I found Linda's classmates.
在大象这边
Look for the elephants.
大多数的物种在很长一段时间都不进化
Most species stay in stasis for long periods of time.
-抱歉  有什么需要  -我是加调局的里斯本探员
- Sorry, can I help you? - I'm Agent Lisbon with the CBI.
-你是弗里德曼教授吗  -客座教授
- Professor Friedman? - Adjunct Professor.
对  客座教授保罗·弗里德曼
Yes, Adjunct Professor Paul Friedman,
你也看到了  学生们都对我
which, as you can see, engenders a great deal of respect
非常敬重
from the students.
我在基德教授手下教课
Uh, I teach a couple seminars under Dr. Kidd.
抱歉打断你了
I'm sorry to interrupt,
我是来调查琳达·帕弗瑞的情况的
but I'm looking for information on Linda Parfrey.
这些都是她的同学  对吗
These are her classmates, right?
对  我们都认识琳达
Yeah. Uh, we all know Linda.
你们知道什么能协助
Do you know anything that might be helpful
调查的线索吗
with the investigation?
我们知道琳达有个男友
We know that Linda had a boyfriend.
我们想找他谈谈
Uh, we'd like to talk to him.
应该是前男友吧
Ex-boyfriend, I guess.
她不怎么谈这事  可有一晚在实验室
She didn't talk much about it, but late one night in the lab,
她告诉我他们分手了
she told me they broke up.
什么时候的事
When was that?
大概是她失踪前一周
About a week before she went missing.
你不会怀疑是他干的吧
You don't think he did it, do you?
他可是个警察
I mean, he's a cop.
-警察  知道名字吗  -知道
- A cop? Do you know his name? - Yeah.
旧金山警局的雷·莫兰警官
Officer Ray Moran, San Francisco P.D.
片警
Beat cop.
好  和他的队长谈谈
All right, talk to his captain.
问问能不能把他带来局里问话
See if we can bring Moran in for an interview.
让周问话  也叫上简  如果他来了的话
Put Cho on it. Jane, too, if he ever comes in.
好
You got it.
头儿
Hey, boss?
我成功了  我考入了培训计划
I did it. I made it into the program.
白帽黑客  你考上了  真不错
White hat? You got in? That's great.
对  在洛杉矶培训一个月
Yeah. A month in L.A.
虽然我还是会一直盯着电脑屏幕
I'll be staring at a computer screen the whole time,
可还是很棒
but still.
大家都会想你的
The team's gonna miss you.
你说会帮我向伯特仑申请助学金的
You said you'd talk to Bertram about the stipend request.
两天后就得交保证金了
The deposit's due in two days.
我回去路上会找他
I'll swing by on my way back.
谢了  头儿
Thanks, boss.
这叫做白帽黑客
It's called white hat.
这是由真正黑客教授的先进的
It's an advanced computer investigation training program
电脑调查培训项目
taught by actual hackers.
非常高级
It's so advanced,
她给我介绍的时候我都听不太明白
I don't know what she's saying when she talks about it.
我想马上申请培训津贴
I'd like to rush a request for a training stipend
帮她支付培训费用
to cover the costs.
你觉得曼彻斯特出老千了吗
You think Manchester's been cheating?
-什么  -打牌时候
- What? - At poker.
没
No.
他太得意了
Well, he's just s-so damn smug.
《月亮晚安》  他说
You know, "Goodnight moon," he says--
那是什么意思
What the hell is that?
只是打牌而已
It's just a game.
你自己都不信吧
You don't believe that.
长官
Sir...
不  对了  范佩尔是什么事
No--oh, what was that about Van Pelt?
她的培训津贴
Her training stipend.
时间很紧
Times are tight.
我们砍了所有外部培训金的预算
We've cut all outside training funds from the budget.
不行  没法拨款
No, request denied.
里斯本说联系不上你
Lisbon said she lost you.
我带了礼物来
Well, I come bearing gifts.
格蕾斯
Grace.
恐龙果冻是给我的
Jelly dinosaurs are for me...
以后吃
For later.
还有...
And...
-我猜你喜欢三角龙  -对
- I'm guessing you're a Triceratops man. - Yeah.
而瑞斯比喜欢霸王龙
Rigsby is a T. Rex.
案情有新进展吗
Any news on the case?
有  死者的前男友是旧金山警察
Yeah, the victim's ex-boyfriend is an S.F.P.D. beat cop.
现在正在巡逻  我正要去找他问话
He's on patrol right now. I was just gonna go talk to him.
-出警吗  -对
- On the streets? - Yeah.
走吧  我有段时间没出警了
Let's go. I haven't been on the streets for a while.
走吧
Let's do it.
-走吧  -不谢我吗
- Come on. - Thanks?
我不知道  他大概五尺六
I don't know. He was like, uh, 5'6".
体型不算胖  脸很大
Not fat, really. Just a big face.
棕色头发
Brown hair.
他都没有持枪  你为什么给他钱
He didn't even have a gun. Why'd you give him the money?
我没给他  是他自己拿走的
I didn't give it to him, he took it!
这家伙什么打扮
What was he dressed like, this guy?
你们是加调局的吗
You guys from CBI?
我是周探员  这位是派翠克·简
Agent Cho. This is Patrick Jane.
我很愿意配合你们工作
Uh, look, I want to talk to you guys,
可我得先把手头的事处理完
but we gotta handle this, okay?
我过几个小时找你们吧
Let me catch up with you in a couple hours.
-几个小时  -对  我们刚接警
- A couple hours? - Yeah, we just got this.
我们得发布犯罪通报
I mean, we gotta put out a crime broadcast.
还得片区巡逻
We gotta cruise the neighborhood.
然后写报告
Then there's the paperwork.
你的报告我是爱莫能助了
Well, can't help you with the paperwork.
-他戴着兜帽  走进来  -你为什么把钱给他
- He had a hood. He came in... - Why'd you give him the money?
先生  请由我们来问话
Sir, we're asking the questions here.
告诉我事发经过
Just tell me what happened.
我从收银机取钱时这家伙走进来
So this dude comes up while I'm cashing out the register,
问我要名片
asks for a calling card.
我只转过身一秒钟
I just turned for one second,
他就把手伸进窗口抢了一摞20块
and he reached through the gap and grabbed a stack of $20s.
你得等到取完钞
You wait until you're finished cashing out
才能做另一笔交易
before you do another transaction!
听着  这家伙拿着钱
Look, the guy had money.
他看上去没什么可疑的
He didn't look shady or anything.
我怎么会知道他会抢钱
How was I supposed to know?
请问
Hey. Excuse me.
给我演示一下他手伸进来够钱的情景
Show me how he reached through the gap again.
好了  手缩回去
All right. Pull your hand out.
这就是抓浣熊的方法  你知道吗
That's how they catch a raccoon, you know that?
这么说  那家伙没法通过这个口抢钱
So the guy couldn't have grabbed the cash through the gap.
根本没有这个人  是吗  哥们
There wasn't another guy, was there, buddy?
是你  你就是小偷
You! You're the thief!
我是小偷
I'm the thief?
你就是小偷
You're the thief.
你就付我那么点工资  反倒说我是小偷
With what you're paying me, I'm the thief?
活儿干完了  哥们
Work's done here, buddy.
我想你们可以把小偷带去做笔录了
I think you can get your man to do the paperwork.
听着
Look--
不不不
No, no, no.
你和琳达什么时候认识的
When did you and Linda meet?
去年  我在值夜班
Last year. I was moonlighting,
在博物馆做安保
doing security at the museum.
你们的感情生活如何
And how was the relationship?
她的生活比我认识的任何人都稳当
Her life was more together than anybody I ever met.
她很专注
She was so focused.
我想也感染到了我
Got to me, too, I guess.
我甚至开始为警官考试做准备
I even started studying for the sergeant's exam.
然后把她给甩了
Mm-hmm. And then you dumped her?
-你以为我不难过吗  -这要你告诉我们
- You think I was happy about it? - You tell me.
大约两个月前  我收到了一封匿名电邮
About two months ago I got an anonymous e-mail
里面有个链接
with a link in it
是她网上的约会资料
to her online dating profile.
我无法相信
I couldn't believe it.
她已经在和别人交往了吗
And she'd started seeing other people?
我不知道有没有
I... I don't know if she started.
她只是在看有没有更好的
She was just shopping around.
可能她一直都这样吧
Maybe she'd been doing it the whole time.
-你和她聊过这事吗  -聊过
- You talk to her about it? - Yeah.
大吵了一架
Big fight.
你对她动粗了吗
You get rough with her?
没  我不干这种事
Mnh. I don't have that in me.
我不会伤害女人  尤其是琳达
Hurt a woman? Especially not Linda.
她有解释吗
She have an explanation?
她不承认  不过她还能怎么样呢
She denied it, you know, but what else was she gonna do?
我无法接受她脚踏两条船  只好放手了
I can't take cheating. I had to let her go.
你知道资料是谁发给你的吗
Mm-hmm. Did you know who sent you the profile?
-不知道  -你不好奇吗
- No. - And you weren't curious?
我不知道  我...
I don't know. I...
某个人的女友和我同病相怜
Some guy's girlfriend's in the same boat as me,
有人心存怨恨
somebody's holding a grudge.
唯一重要的是  我配不上她
Only thing that mattered was I wasn't enough for her.
分手后  你没再和她联系过吗
And after you broke up, you never spoke to her again?
没
No.
我早该知道的
I should have known.
她很有头脑
You know, she had smarts.
她会大有作为
She was gonna have a big life.
她怎么会想要我这样的小人物呢
What'd she want with a mook like me, right?
有什么进展吗
Do you have something?
这是别人传给莫兰的约会资料
Here's the dating profile somebody sent Moran.
东方海湾
查查这个交友网站
Get a hold of the dating site.
看是否有人在她失踪前后联系过她
See if anybody contacted her around the time she went missing.
我觉得琳达没和人约会
I don't think Linda went on any dates.
为什么
Well, why not?
发送莫兰这封电邮的地址
The address that sent Moran the e-mail
正是建立这个交友账户的邮箱地址
was used to set up an account with the dating site.
你找到了吗
Did you find them?
算是吧  我登陆了账户
Sort of. I logged into the account.
你不需要密码吗
Don't you need a password for that?
我用最常见的密码试了两分钟
I spent two minutes using the most common passwords.
是"Qwerty"
It was "Qwerty."
"Qwerty"
"Qwerty"?
Q-w-e-r-t-y
Q-w-e-r-t-y.
这是最常见的密码第五位
It's the fifth most common password.
猜猜是谁的资料
Guess whose profile it was.
琳达
Linda.
那发给莫兰资料的人就是创建账户的人
So whoever sent Moran the profile also created it.
对  资料是伪造的
Yep. Profile's a fake.
有人想拆散琳达和莫兰警官
Someone was trying to break up Linda and officer Moran.
干得好
Nice work. Mm.
听着  我知道你没去成培训计划很失望
Look, I know you're disappointed about the training program.
我们明年送你去
We'll get you in next year.
没事
It's fine.
伯特仑本应该打的得心应手
Bertram's supposed to be this real smooth player,
但他却输了好几把牌
but he loses a couple of hands of poker
还惹恼了跟他打牌的人
and he has to bum everybody else out.
琳达想找一个"身材火辣的男人"
Linda wanted "A man with a super hot body."
你是在说伪造的交友简介
The fake dating profile, right?
你刚才在说什么
You were saying something?
伯特仑把范佩尔给坑惨了
Bertram hanging Van Pelt out to dry.
他打牌输了很多钱  就变得歇斯底里了
He's just mad because he's losing big money at poker.
有些人就是喜欢把他们的痛苦凌驾于他人之上
Well, some people like to push their pain onto other people,
软弱的人  总是有人更软弱的
weaker people, and there's always someone weaker.
这就是生命的轮回啊
That's just the circle of life.
好吧
Cheery.
里斯本  伯特仑不是想赢  是必须赢
Bertram doesn't want to win, Lisbon, he has to.
所以他才会在现在的位子上
It's why he is where he is.
对他而言  输是不可忍受的
The idea of losing is just intolerable to him.
为什么会有人想拆散琳达和她男友呢
Why would somebody want to break Linda and her boyfriend up?
情敌
Romantic rivalry?
有可能
Yeah, possibly.
"我在找有头脑  有肌肉  全面的男人"
"I'm looking for brains, brawn, the total package."
范佩尔试着追踪电子邮件
Van Pelt's trying to trace the e-mail,
但毫无收获
but she hit a dead end.
不管是谁做的肯定留下了线索
Well, whoever authored this left their fingerprints all over it.
"半吊子不行"
"No half-steppers.
"我在找一个真正的坏小子
"A genuine badass.
装点我的小巢"
Feather my nest."
把人都喊来  里斯本
Gather the troops, Lisbon.
为啥
Why?
咱们来玩宾果游戏
It's time to play bingo.
我们从伪造的约会资料里提取了一些词
So we have a list of words from the fake dating profile.
我们和学生们谈谈
We talk to the students
对比学生们的用词
and compare what they say to the words in the list,
如果他们的用词和列表上的词相吻合
and if what they say matches up with the words on the list,
那他们就是伪造资料的人吗
Then they're the one that wrote the profile?
你说的没错
So far, so good.
但我们怎么让他们说出这些词呢
But how do we get them to say the right words?
我们该问他们些什么
What do we ask them about?
让他们不停的说话就行了
You have to try to get their words flowing.
-谈谈他们喜欢的东西  -喜欢的东西
- Talk to them about their passions. - Their passions?
当然是动物
Animals, of course.
虫子  以及小动物
Bugs. Critters.
人们用"冷血"来表示邪恶
People use "Coldblooded" to mean evil,
就好像物种的体温调节特性
as if a species' thermophysiology
能够决定它们的道德属性一样
could determine its moral attributes.
这太荒唐了
That's ridiculous.
爬行动物永远也发明不了原子弹
Reptiles never invented the atomic bomb.
要我说  恒温动物才是问题的所在
If you ask me, warm blood is the problem.
明白我的意思吗
Know what I mean?
失陪一下
Excuse me.
说说...骷髅吧
So... skeletons.
你为什么喜欢骷髅
Why are you into them?
为什么一定要有原因呢
Why do I need a reason?
我就当你是不正常了
I'll just go with "Weird."
这就像是在我们的五脏六腑之下
It's, like, under all this viscera we wear,
有一些很强壮  很干净
there's--well, there's something strong and--and clean
很美丽的东西  把它们组合在了一起
and--and beautiful that--that holds us together.
没它们还真不行  我觉得这很酷
You can't lose it. I think--I think that's cool.
我通过了吗
Did I pass?
我之前接受过精神分析测试
I've taken a psych test before.
简先生
Mr. Jane.
我们刚才还谈到了你
We were just discussing you.
帕帕达基斯院长和我说了你惊人的记忆力
Dean Papadakis told me about your impressive memory.
我现在的记忆力大不如前了
My own memory isn't as good as it used to be.
你有什么秘诀吗
What's your secret?
不要忘记就行了
It's easy to remember when you never forget.
你在做什么
What you doing?
放置捕捉飞蛾的诱饵
Laying bait for moths.
它们喜欢甜味
They like sweetness,
所以我就用芝麻蕉和啤酒做饵
so I use brown bananas and beer.
真美味
Delicious.
保罗在这里发现了一个全新的飞蛾物种
Paul here discovered a new species of moth.
加利福尼亚绿玉蛾
The California Jade Moth.
在我们的博物馆里就有展出
It's on display in our museum.
真是件了不起的大事
It's rather a big deal.
是啊  现在世界上的芸芸昆虫又多了一种
Yeah. Now there are 1,500,001 types of insects in the world.
这谦虚可真假
Well, that's false modesty.
我想是的  这的确是件大事
I guess so. It is a big deal.
对研究蛾的人来说
To moth people.
是对我们大家来说
To all of us.
恭喜你获得新发现
Congratulations on your new addition.
-谢谢  -令人印象深刻
- Thank you. - It's most impressive.
谢谢
Thank you.
让我猜猜  你是在研究秃鹰
Uh, let me guess. You're studying buzzards,
而你还设好了陷阱
and you're laying a trap for one right now.
说的跟真的一样
As if.
我研究的是"加州海狮的交配习惯"
Mating habits of the Zalophus Californianus.
海狮
Sea lions.
雄海狮靠打斗吸引一群雌海狮  像个坏小子
One badass male maintaining a stable of females through combat.
那很吸引你吗  有个能为你大打出手的男人
And that appeals to you? A man fighting for you?
谁不想找个霸道的男人
Who doesn't want an alpha male?
一个会为他的东西大打出手的男人
A guy who will fight for what's his?
超级火辣
Yeah. Super hot.
听起来不错
Sounds exciting.
很酷的  当保罗在追逐蛾子
It's so cool. While Paul chases moths
而珍妮特和她的蜥蜴混在一起的时候
and Jeanette messes around with her lizards,
我正在海岛间穿梭观察海豹
I head out for the islands to watch the seals play.
我不光只有脑子  瞧见没
I'm not just a brain, see?
我还喜欢玩
I like to play, too.
我是全方位的
I'm the total package.
坏小子  热辣  全方位
"Badass," "Super hot," "Total package."
全中
Bingo!
是你伪造了约会资料
You wrote the fake dating profile
导致了琳达和她男友分手
that made Linda and her boyfriend break up.
这也没犯法啊  对吧
No law against it, is there?
也许她发现了是你干的
Maybe she found out it was you,
在实验室里找你对质  接着事情就失控了
confronted you in the lab, and things got out of hand.
听着  我没杀琳达
Look--hello! I didn't kill Linda.
那你为什么要拆散他们
So why did you want to break them up?
你是不知道项目组里的情况
You don't even know what it's like in the program.
基德博士希望我们像欢乐的一家人一样
Dr. Kidd likes us to play like we're one happy family.
但我们就像一群鬣狗一样  撕咬着对方
We're like a pack of hyenas tearing each other apart.
为什么
Why?
为了钱  还能为什么
Money. Why else?
博物馆里的东西可不是免费得来的
Look, the museum doesn't get all that stuff for free.
它需要各种发现  宣传和捐助
It needs discoveries, publicity, donations.
基德博士希望我们的项目小组是最棒的
Dr. Kidd wants our program to be the best.
所以如果你没有成果的话  再见了
So if you aren't producing, so long.
这话是什么意思
What does that mean?
你有没有听说过适者生存
You ever heard of survival of the fittest?
基德博士肯定听说过
'cause Dr. Kidd sure has.
她会淘汰到那些没有贡献
She likes to weed out the ones who can't contribute,
不能胜任的人
who can't hack it.
但没人能胜任  根本没有
But nobody hacks it. Not really.
什么意思
What do you mean?
珍妮特  那个蜥蜴女
Jeanette? Lizard girl?
你以为她能留下来  她都要急哭了
She has a special place on the back stairs? She goes to cry.
格雷格去年出了大纰漏
Greg had a major breakdown last year,
比如把老鼠骷髅扔到了窗户外
like throwing rat skulls out the window.
保罗呢  在他发现那该死的蛾子之前
And Paul? He was convinced Dr. Kidd was gonna fire him
他一度确信基德博士就要开除他了
until he discovered that dumb moth.
琳达呢  她是怎么应对的
How about Linda? How did she handle it?
她就像个机器
She was a machine.
我们都快疯了  她却什么事都没有
You're losing your mind, and there she is,
一样辛苦工作  却毫不费劲
working just as hard, not even breaking a sweat.
而我呢  因为没拿到
My mom wanted to kill me
院长的奖学金  我妈差点要杀了我
for not getting the dean's fellowship.
接着琳达遇到了她那个性感的警察男友
And then Linda lands that hot cop boyfriend?
就凭她
Her?
我是说
I mean...
看看
Right?
所以你伪造了约会资料想让他们分手
So you made up the fake dating profile to break them up.
我只是想看看  我能不能伤到她
I just wanted to see if I could hurt her.
或者她能不能被伤害到
If she could even be hurt.
她知道是你干的吗
Did she know it was you?
这件事毁了她
It wrecked her.
第二天  她做了一些很愚蠢的事情
The next day she messed up something stupid,
基德博士还朝她大吼来着
and Dr. Kidd yelled at her.
你知道吗
You know what?
这让我感觉真的很好
It felt really, really good.
我知道  这让我听上去像个坏人
And I know that doesn't make me sound like a nice person.
对  还真不是好人
No. No, it doesn't.
有点像"蝇王"的桥段啊
It's like "Lord of the Flies" over there.
英国作家威廉·戈尔丁的代表作  借小孩的天真来探讨人性的恶
我不知道原来科学世界是如此的残酷
I didn't know the world of science was so cutthroat.
人们不是常说  因为风险极小
Well, like the man said, academic politics
学术政治也会充满恶意
can be vicious, because the stakes are small.
事实上风险非常小
Very small, indeed.
明天早上我们回博物馆一趟
Tomorrow morning we need to go back to the museum.
为什么
Why?
去教育
Education.
但现在我得做些事情
But now I have to do something.
检察长很清楚  控告不会坚持到最后
And the A.G. knows damn well the indictment won't stick.
我现在没空和你谈
Uh, I don't have time for this.
天下没有免费的午餐  这道理他懂
Nobody rides for free. I mean, he knows that.
怎么  你过来找我打扑克吗
What--what, you came here to play games?
我听说你输得挺惨
I heard you've been losing,
还影响到了你的工作
and, uh, it's been affecting your work.
我再打给你
Uh, I'll call you back.
扑克根本没影响我的工作
Look, the cards haven't been falling my way.
得了吧
Oh, come on.
你相信运气吗
You believe in luck?
不
No.
里斯本说你很厉害
Lisbon says you're pretty good.
玛格丽特  取消六点的安排
Margaret, cancel my 6:00.
两对
Two pair.
四条[四张同点]
Four of a kind.
瞧见没
See?
我知道怎么玩扑克
I know how to play poker.
你当然知道
Of course you do.
你擅长玩弄人  而不是牌
You play the man, not the cards.
对吧  我懂机率  我了解我自己
Right? I know the odds, I know myself.
你了解人性  知道如何操纵他们
You know people, you know how to control them.
却不善利用
Not that you always care.
什么意思
Uh... what's that mean?
要多抓苍蝇  蜂蜜比醋有效
Well, you win more flies with honey than with vinegar,
但你却非用醋
but you use vinegar anyway.
你是为里斯本来的吧
Is this about Lisbon?
你很喜欢虚张声势  是吧
You're very fond of the fake tell, aren't you?
你押注前  会四处张望  缓慢呼气
Before you bet, you look away and you breathe out very slowly,
看似想让自己平静下来
like you're trying to... calm yourself.
没错
Yes.
其实你有破绽
Well, you have a tell inside the fake tell.
当你这么做的时候
When you're bluffing,
别人能听见你的呼吸声
the breathing is audible.
说什么呢  我能控制住自己
The hell it is. I-I control myself.
你拿到好牌以后  就像那样呼吸
You get yourself a good hand and puff away like that,
曼彻斯特一定以为你在虚张声势
Manchester will for sure think you're bluffing.
相信我
Trust me.
简先生  有什么可以效劳
Mr. Jane. Can I help you?
但愿吧  你还想学我的记忆诀窍吗
I hope so. Uh, you still want to learn my memory trick?
当然
I would.
好  你要给琳达的同学们
Yeah, you teach a master class
上研修课的  是吧
with all of Linda's fellow classmates, huh?
今天下午的课  是我和保罗来上
Paul and I will be teaching it this afternoon.
这样啊
Yeah.
那我给你和你的学生
Well, how about I put on a memory seminar
来场记忆讲座如何
for you and your class?
再好不过了
That would be terrific.
不过你不是有谋杀案要破吗
But don't you have a murder to solve?
来得及
Eh, all in good time.
我需要几张桌子
Uh, I'm gonna need some tables,
大概三到四张排在那后面
possibly three or four across the back there.
好的
Okay.
还有  琳达的办公室里有很多动物标本
And, uh, Linda's office, it's full of animals-- dead ones.
是的
It is.
那些也要  做道具用
We'll need access to that, uh, for props.
好的  我猜
Okay. I assume...
你这么做一定另有意图吧
that you have some ulterior motive for all of this.
你们有怀疑对象了吗
Do you have a suspect?
有件事我要向你求证一下
There's one thing I'd like you to confirm for me.
什么事
What is that?
北扑翅鴷以什么为食
Just what is the diet of the northern flicker woodpecker?
好的  当然
Yeah. Sure.
你怎么会喜欢三角龙
How can you like Triceratops
而不是霸王龙
more than... T-rex?
霸王龙都是废物
T-rex are losers.
小胳膊小腿的  不过是长了牙的大型鸡
Little arms. It's a big chicken with teeth.
是吗  那三角龙根本就是长了角的猪
Yeah, and Triceratops is basically a pig with horns.
可它头上长着盾牌呢
And a shield on its head.
分分钟秒杀你那巨型鸡
Beats a giant chicken any day of the week.
做梦去吧  简有什么事
Ha ha, in your dreams. What did Jane want?
他叫我们回博物馆去
He wants us back at the museum.
回去干嘛
What are we gonna do?
-抢劫博物馆  -为什么
- Museum heist. - Why?
我早就不问这些问题了  走吧
I stopped asking questions a long time ago. Come on.
这是干嘛
What's this all about?
我们只是不想有任何遗漏  先生
We just need to cover our bases, sir.
这跟调查有什么关系
What does this have to do with the investigation?
我不能透露在办案件的细节
I can't discuss ongoing details of an investigation.
我得看看这些蜘蛛
I'm gonna need to look at one of these, uh, spiders.
狼蛛吗
The tarantulas?
孩子们  来看这些蜘蛛啊
Hey, kids, come check this out. Spiders.
对了  叫狼蛛
Oh, yes. The tarantulas.
我看没必要吧
I don't see why it is necessary.
别担心  先生  警方只是例行公事
Don't worry, sir. This is, uh, official police business.
你们一定想看看...
I'm sure you want to take...
等等  你要干嘛
Wait! What are you doing?
-我得近距离观察一下这只蜘蛛  -不行
- I'm gonna need to take a close look at this spider here. - No.
就是这只蜘蛛
This one specifically here, this spider.
不行  不行  你要干嘛
No, no, what are you doing?
来吧
Here we go.
不行  求你了
Just-- no. Oh, oh, please.
多加小心
Be very careful.
来吧  太好了
There we go. Uh, yeah.
我看没这个必要吧
I-I don't see why this is necessary.
别害怕  孩子们
Don't worry, children, it's...
好了  来吧
Uh, yeah... there we go.
等等  你在干嘛
Wait, what are you doing?
好了  我们得...
Yeah, we're gonna have to, uh...
-采集它的指纹  -什么
- dust this for prints. - Do what?
颜色真漂亮  是吧  孩子们
Oh, pretty colors. Huh, kids?
我被咬了
It bit--it bit me.
慢着  你说什么
Oh, wait. What?
我被它咬了
It bit me.
我去叫人来吧
Let me call somebody,
这个很危险
this can be a danger.
看  看见没有  我死定了
Look. See? It's deadly.
我感觉怪怪的
It feels a little strange.
-什么都看不出来  -我头晕了
- I don't see anything. - Oh, I'm feeling woozy.
没有  我开玩笑的  我没事
No, I'm just kidding. I'm fine.
别玩蜘蛛  孩子们  懂了吗
Don't play with spiders, kids. Okay?
我们今天有福了
We've got a real treat today.
可以称之为"现实版进化论"
You could call it "Evolution in Action."
派翠克·简先生将给我们做一场
Mr. Patrick Jane is coming to give us a seminar
有关记忆力上限的讲座
on the upper limits of memory.
-我们到教室了吧  -是的  到了
- Are we in the classroom? - Yes, we are.
太棒了
Great.
人类的记忆能力通常比人们意识到的要强
The human memory is far more capable than most people realize.
我之前进过这个房间
I've been in this room once before.
我当时来的时候
But when I was in here...
观察了一下
I paid attention.
观察得非常仔细
Very close attention.
谢谢  不过这只是记忆力方面的小儿科
Oh, thank you. Please. But that's just memory 101.
让我们转入高级课程吧
Let's move forward into the advanced coursework.
要想记忆力发挥作用
For memory to be useful,
就必须使其如照相机一般精准和迅速
it has to be as accurate and as fast as a camera.
你拿了多少动物  里斯本
How many animals did you get, Lisbon?
大概三十个
Around 30.
是从琳达的办公室里拿的吧
And you got them from Linda's office?
是  没错
Yes, I did.
所有的动物都来自琳达的办公室
All of the animals came from Linda's office.
之前我从没去过那儿
That's a place that I have never been.
一会儿  我会回过头
And in a moment, I will turn around
看我身后的东西  只需要几秒钟
and look behind me-- and just for a few seconds--
我就能按顺序记住桌上的所有动物
and I will memorize every animal on those tables in order.
然后我会教你们如何做到这一点
And then I will show you how you can do the same.
谁知道你是不是已经背下来了
How do we know you didn't already memorize them?
有个怀疑论者  我该想到的
Ah. A skeptic. I should have known.
不过你说得对
And you're right.
你们没道理要相信我
There's no reason for you to trust me.
保罗  你能不能把那些动物
Paul, would you mind rearranging the animals
按你认为合适的方式重新摆放
any way you see fit?
没问题
Sure.
谢谢
Thank you.
人类的大脑
The human brain.
只要运用得当  就能异常高效
Once you get it working right, it can be incredibly effective.
我们的大脑能作出很多不可思议的事情
The mind can do some miraculous things.
比如  预知未来
Uh, like... telling the future.
正如我现在所做的一样
Which is what I'm doing right now.
吹牛
Bull.
你要是这么说
For that...
就由你来拿着这个预言吧
You can be the one who holds the prediction.
科学就是预言  不是吗
Science is about prediction, isn't it?
是以确实的数据为基础的预言  不是算命
Predictions based on hard data, not fortunetelling.
表达不同而已
Ahh. Well, you say "Tomato,"
我认为科学家推崇理性思维
I say scientists believe in rational thought.
表格  列表  分类
And grids and lists and classification,
这些都没问题  可世界不是这么运转的
which is fine, but it's not how the world works,
当然大脑也并非如此运转的
and it's certainly not how the brain works.
你是说人是非理性的吗
You're saying people aren't rational?
保持理性只是一种手段
Well, being rational is a tool,
但并非我们掌握的唯一手段
but it's not the only tool we have.
早在我们把知识填进图表前
Long before we stuffed our knowledge into graphs and charts,
我们就用上了很多古老的方式  有时候
we used older and, in some cases,
是更为有趣的方式来记事
more entertaining ways to remember things.
怎么样了  保罗
How we doing there, Paul?
-好了  -太好了  请坐吧
- I think we're good. - Excellent. Please, take a seat.
现在  我要让你们见识一下我的理论
Now, I'd like to show you what I'm talking about.
里斯本  劳驾
Lisbon, uh, would you mind?
多谢
Thank you.
我们可以在大脑中建造一座宫殿来帮助记忆
We can create a memory by building a palace in our minds.
我们可以给自己唱首歌
We can sing ourselves a song,
或是讲个小故事
or tell ourselves a little story.
这是个恶霸的故事
A story of a bully--
一只灰色的狐狸
a gray fox--
和一个小个子勇士
and a little brave man--
一只老鼠
a rat--
他为他胖乎乎的兄弟癞蛤蟆
that stood up for his chubby little buddy the toad
和他的朋友蛋头出头
and his friend egghead.
接着是个穿燕尾服的男人的故事
The story of a man in a tuxedo
他在人群中钻来钻去
who snaked his way through a crowd
只为去见一位身着华服的女人
to meet a woman in a colorful dress.
企鹅  蟒蛇  三只松鼠  还有一只鹦鹉
Penguin, cobra, three squirrels, and a parrot.
接着是个关于飞行的故事
The story of flight...
猫头鹰  蝙蝠  飞蛾
An owl, a bat, a moth,
全部...
All...
看来我说错了
Ah, I sense I made a mistake.
没有飞蛾
No moth.
也许我的预言能解释我犯的错
Well, perhaps my prediction will explain my error.
珍妮特  请读出来  好吗
Uh, Jeanette, could you read it out, please?
飞蛾在保罗的口袋里
"The moth is in Paul's pocket"?
等等  什么
Wait, what?
那只飞蛾
The moth.
那只你重新摆放动物时
The moth you stole from the table
从桌上偷走的飞蛾
when you were rearranging the animals--
在你口袋里面
It's in your pocket.
我需要你清空你的口袋
I'm gonna need you to empty your pockets.
快点
Come on.
让我们看看
Let's have a look.
保罗  你拿这只飞蛾做什么
Paul, why did you take the moth?
那是只加利福尼亚绿玉蛾
That's a California Jade Moth.
-是的  -这物种是他发现的
- So it is. - The kind he discovered.
我以为唯一的一只收藏在博物馆里
I thought the only other one was in the museum.
-那这只是从哪儿来的  -等一下
- Where did that come from? - Wait a second.
你说过所有的动物
You said all the animals
都是从琳达办公室拿来的
came from Linda's office.
是从那儿拿的
They did.
保罗在琳达死后才发现了这种飞蛾
Linda died before Paul discovered the moth.
这飞蛾不可能是从她办公室拿的
This moth couldn't have come from her... office.
你会想明白的
You'll get there.
除非  是她先发现的这种飞蛾
Unless... she discovered the moth first.
保罗
Paul...
不会是你杀了琳达吧
You didn't kill Linda.
对  就是他
Yes, he did.
但是  我承认
But, uh, I confess--
那只飞蛾不是我从琳达办公室拿的
that moth didn't come from Linda's office.
我
I...
偷
s--
我从博物馆借出来的
Well, I-I borrowed it from the museum...
为了证明我的观点
to prove a point.
保罗
Paul.
之前我的论文被退稿了
I'd just had a paper rejected.
被同行评审打回了
Peer review threw it back at me.
基德博士非常失望
Dr. Kidd was so disappointed.
她从没说过什么
She never said anything.
她也不需要说
She never had to.
琳达的死跟这些事有什么关系
How did Linda come into it?
那天半夜在实验室里
It was late night at the lab.
她刚刚从森林里回来  非常兴奋
Uh, she came in fresh from the forest, excited.
她看到她的一只啄木鸟正在吃一只
Uh, she'd seen one of her woodpeckers eating a moth
她说不出种类的飞蛾
that she couldn't identify.
所以她放了些诱饵并抓住了一只
So she put down some bait and caught one.
我们在她的办公室找到了红糖
We found the brown sugar in her office.
就是她的诱饵吗
Was that her bait?
对
Yeah.
当我看到它的一瞬间我就知道这它是什么
I knew what it was the moment I saw it.
一个新物种
A new species.
它将带来新文章
I mean, that's articles,
博物馆展览
that's museum exhibits,
为项目带来资金
that's money for the program.
我看到未来由我自己命名这种飞蛾
I saw myself naming the moth.
我一直都想要给什么东西命名
I'd--I'd always wanted to name something.
我的工作岌岌可危
My job was on the line.
还有我的未来
My future.
我需要这只飞蛾
I needed it...
来度过难关
to survive.
我完全失去了理智
I just lost myself completely.
当我回过神以后
I came back to my senses,
把现场收拾干净
I cleaned up,
在我们实验室有很多种清理血迹的方法
lots of ways to clean blood in our lab.
然后  我让蠕虫来处理琳达
And then, I gave Linda to the worms.
之后我去了琳达之前
Then I went out to the part of the forest
发现飞蛾的
where I knew she'd been
那片树林
discovered the moth.
然后回来将这一切据为己有
I came back and got my accolades.
我保住了我的工作
I saved my job.
得到了一切我渴望的东西
I got everything I wanted.
基德博士
Dr. Kidd.
请叫我索尼亚
Sonia, please.
我想要感谢你抓住了保罗
I wanted to thank you for catching Paul.
你不必客气
Ah. There's no thanks necessary.
琳达死了  保罗进了监狱
Linda's dead, Paul's in jail,
梅根将被开除
and Megan is being expelled.
我想这个项目永远不会恢复了
I don't think the program will ever recover.
项目并不是真实存在的
The program isn't real.
问题是  你能从中恢复吗
The question is, will you recover?
我觉得非常无力
I felt so powerless.
我是说  面对死亡你又能做什么呢
I mean, what can you do in the face of death?
但是你并不软弱无力
You're not powerless, though.
你会行动
You act.
至少你可以做这件事
Well, there's one thing you can do.
保罗通过命名那种飞蛾获得了很多的荣誉
Uh... Paul took a lot of pride in naming that moth, when...
但实际上应该是琳达来命名它
When it should have been Linda who named it.
没错
Yes.
我会确保飞蛾将重新以她来命名
I'll make sure to rename it after her.
谢谢你
Thank you.
是我的荣幸
Pleasure.
对
Yeah.
讲得通
Makes sense.
好男人都有主了
All the good ones are taken.
得了吧
Please.
我想是物竞天择
Natural selection, I suppose.
行啦
Come on.
再见  派翠克
Good-bye, Patrick.
再见  索尼亚
Good-bye, Sonia.
跟道金斯五百美元
$500 to Dawkins.
不跟
Nope.
我要
I'll, uh...
加注一百美元
raise $100.
看来我不得不再加注一百美元
Well, I'm just gonna have to raise you another $100.
你怎么就学不会呢  盖尔
When are you gonna learn, Gale?
再加注一千美元
Raise $1,000.
全押上
All in.
两对
Two pair.
同花
Flush.
同花更大
Flush takes the pot.
"晚安  月亮"
"Goodnight moon."
以下皆源自美国儿童读物《晚安  月亮》
"晚安  星星"
"Goodnight stars."
晚安  大法官
Goodnight Judge.
你看到没  你刚才看到没
You see that? Did you see that?
同花吗  非常带劲
The flush? It was very nice.
我把他赢光了
Ah, I gutted him!
我也这么想
I would say so, yeah.
你很聪明  让简来给我上课
That was very slick, you having Jane give me lessons.
看来你真得很想帮范佩尔
You must really want to help Van Pelt.
简到底做了什么
What did Jane do?
现在就不要再装了
Oh, now there's no need to be coy.
我会给你回报的
I don't have a problem with a little quid pro quo.
白帽黑客项目  对吗
The white hat program, wasn't it?
明早我就会批准津贴
I'll authorize the stipend in the morning.
谢谢你  长官
Thank you, Sir.
不  不  多谢你
No, no. Thank you.
-还要谢谢简  -我会的
- And thank Jane. - I will.
一些科学家认为霸王龙
And some scientists think the T.Rex could run
一小时可以跑45英里[72.4公里]
up to 45 miles an hour.
它是顶级捕食者
That's apex predator.
-你知道这意味着什么吗  -是的
- You know what that means? - Yes.
这意味着它们是食物链的最顶端
That means they're top of the food chain.
-它们能吃掉任何动物  -所以呢
- They eat everything. - So?
所以霸王龙比三角龙更强  我赢了
So... T. Rex beats Triceratops. I win.
你昨晚回家百度了恐龙
You went home last night and googled dinosaurs,
-是不是  -没错  我查了
- didn't you? - Yeah, I did.
你连生活都没  我赢了
You have no life. I win.
我昨天欠她的
I owe her from yesterday.
她正在去机场的路上
She's on her way to the airport.
对  为了那个什么白帽项目的事
Oh. Yeah, for that white hat thing.
不是说没有津贴吗
I thought there's no money for that.
里斯本解决了
Lisbon fixed it.
要是能说声再见就好了
Would have been nice to say good-bye.
对啊  胆小鬼可没机会
Yeah, well, cowards don't get to say good-bye
说再见
when they want.
胆小...
Cow--wow.
你为什么这么说  你叫我胆小鬼
Where'd that come from? You calling me a coward?
没错
Yep.
此话怎讲
How so?
你假装没有爱着范佩尔
How long have you been pretending
装了多长时间了
you're not in love with Van Pelt?
谁说我爱着范佩尔了
Who says I'm in love with Van Pelt?
我很久以前有过  但之后再没有了
I was once, a long time ago, but not anymore.
我们只是  只不过是  好朋友
We're just... we're just... good friends.
你是个胆小鬼和糟糕的骗子
You're a coward and terrible liar.
你胡扯
Uh... says you.
胆小鬼  他懂什么是恋爱吗
"Coward." What does he know about relationships?
你就跟怀孕的妓女约会
Yeah, well, you date pregnant hookers
而且你的恐龙是吃草的
and your-- your dinosaur eats grass!
-早  -早上好
- Morning. - Good morning.
这段时间我们人手会不够
We're gonna be short-staffed for a while.
范佩尔启程去洛杉矶了
Van Pelt's off to L.A.
谢谢你
Thank you.
成人教育是很美好的事
Adult education's a beautiful thing.
说到这
Uh, speaking of which, uh...
我破坏了扑克游戏的生态系统
I've upset the ecosystem of the poker game.
我想你在博物馆呆了太久了
I think you've been spending too much time at the museum.
"破坏了生态系统"
"Upset the ecosystem"?
全靠我  伯特仑现在牌技进步了
Bertram's now a better poker player because of me.
生态系统改变了  你要么适应它要么就死亡
The ecosystem has changed. You need to adapt or die.
谁说我需要帮助的
Who says I need the help?
别想跟我耍花招
Don't try to razzle-dazzle me.
有钱能使鬼推磨
Money talks.
我们用什么来做筹码
What do we use for stakes?
没有筹码怎么打扑克
You can't play poker without stakes.
我已经搞定了
Oh, I have that covered.
食草动物算一  食肉动物算五
Herbivores are worth 1, carnivores are worth 5.
好的
Okay.
发牌
Deal.
你有什么牌
What do you got?
全押了
All in.
你在虚张声势  我跟注
You're bluffing. I call.
你确定
Really?
好吧  你出老千了吗
Okay, are you cheating?
没有
No.
我赢定你了
I'm gonna smoke you.